Guide to the United States War Relocation Authority. Poston, Arizona Relocation Center Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
United States War Relocation Authority. Poston, Arizona Relocation Center collection
1942-1945
MS 803
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6
Scrapbooks, record books, and memorabilia chiefly relating to the educational and library activities at the Relocation Center. Nine scrapbooks made and bound by the students cover topics of academic study as well as their memoirs describing their feelings on being relocated. A printed yearbook is also included.
United States. War Relocation Authority
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Nathan Van Patten. Transferred from the War Collection, 1944.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
The Poston High School Junior Red Cross Out of the Desert scrapbook in box 4 is available via digital surrogate, and the original scrapbook is restricted due to fragility. Patrons must use the digital surrogate instead of the original scrapbook.
Scope and Contents
Scrapbooks, record books, and memorabilia chiefly relating to the educational and library activities at the Relocation Center. Nine scrapbooks made and bound by the students document topics of academic study, student memoirs describing their feelings on being relocated, and Americanization agendas in school curriculum. A printed yearbook is also included.
Emigration and immigration; Japanese Americans -- Evacuation and relocation, 1942-1945; Japanese -- United States; World War, 1939-1945 -- Evacuation of civilians; World War, 1939-1945 -- United States; United States. War Relocation Authority
- Inventory
  - Christmas cards, hand illustrated, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - James Miyasaki, watercolor drawing, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "How to Relocate through a Hostel," mimeographed, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - List is of collection contents, typescript, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Junior Red Cross Council, Poston High School, photograph, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Poston library materials, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Sophomore class, Poston High School Primitive Time, scrapbook, handwritten and illustrated, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Prehistoric Times, scrapbook, handwritten, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Roman History and Medieval History, handwritten, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - European People in a Period of Revolution, typescript, hand illustrated, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - European People of Modern Time, handwritten and illustrated, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - People of the World Since 1878, handwritten, teachers' work sheet laid in, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Poston Summer Demonstration Class, Causes of the War, typescript, 1943 September 3 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Yearbook
    - Campus Echoes, Parker Valley High School, Poston, Arizona, yearbook, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Record books
    - The Novel Hut (Poston Libraries)
      - Adult membership cards, 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Juvenile membership cards, 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Unidentified junior membership book, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified mimeographed book, in Japanese; contains list of Relocation Center leaders, 1944 July 1 (Box 1, Box 17)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Sophomore class, Poston High School, "The American Way of Life," typescript, hand illustrated, 1943 February-June (Box 2)
    - Poston's Japanese library sign, circa 1942-1945 (Box 2)
    - Junior Red Cross, handwritten and illustrated, circa 1944 (Box 2)
    - Poston High School Junior Red Cross, Out of the Desert, History and Set-up of Poston, mimeographed, hand illustrated, 1943 February-June (Box 4)
      Scope and Contents
      Scrapbook compiled by Poston High School Junior Red Cross and mailed to another Junior Red Cross chapter outside of Poston as a gesture of friendship.
      Conditions Governing Access
      The Poston High School Junior Red Cross Out of the Desert scrapbook is available via digital surrogate, and the original scrapbook is restricted due to fragility. Patrons must use the digital surrogate instead of the original scrapbook.
    - Oversized maps, artwork, and signs (Folder 3)